{
"Questions": [
    {
      "question":       "Who is the winner of India's first noble prize ?",
      "optionOne":      "C. V. Raman",
      "optionTwo":      "Kailash Satyarthi",
      "optionThree":    "Amartya Sen",
      "optionFour":     "Rabindra Nath Tagore",
      "rightAnswer":    "optionFour",
      "audiencePoll":   "5, 10, 5, 80, 0",
      "amount":         "5,000",
      "information":    "Poet Rabindranath Tagore won the Nobel Prize for Literature in 1913 for his collection Gitanjali published in London in 1912."
    },
    {
        "question":    "Who was India's first astronaut ?",
        "optionOne":   "Sunita Williams",
        "optionTwo":   "Ritesh Gupta",
        "optionThree": "Rakesh Sharma",
        "optionFour":  "India has no astronauts",
        "rightAnswer": "optionThree",
        "audiencePoll":"20, 5, 65, 15, 0",
        "amount":      "10,000",
        "information": "On April 2, 1984, IAF pilot Rakesh Sharma became the first Indian to travel to space. When the then PM Indira Gandhi asked, \"How does India look from space ?\" Sharma said, \"Sare Jahan Se Achcha!\""
    },
    {
        "question":    "Who Invented The Very First Aeroplane ?",
        "optionOne":   "Riggler & Brothers",
        "optionTwo":   "Andrew Garfield",
        "optionThree": "Winklevoss Brothers",
        "optionFour":  "Wright Brothers",
        "rightAnswer": "optionFour",
        "audiencePoll":"15, 5, 15, 65, 0",
        "amount":      "20,000",
        "information": "Near North Carolina, Orville and Wilbur Wright make the first successful flight in history. The aircraft stayed aloft for 12 seconds and covered 120 feet on its inaugural flight."
    },
    {
        "question":    "Who Was The First Home Minister Of Free India ?",
        "optionOne":   "Jawahar Lal Nehru",
        "optionTwo":   "Sardar Vallabh Bhai Patel",
        "optionThree": "Babu Jagjeevan Ram",
        "optionFour":  "Lal Bahadur Shastri",
        "rightAnswer": "optionTwo",
        "audiencePoll":"5, 90, 3, 2, 0",
        "amount":      "40,000",
        "information": "In addition to being the home minister, Sardar Patel was instrumental in bringing all the princely States under the ambit of India. Also known as Iron Man of India."
    },
    {
        "question":    "How Many Years Did It Take To Build The Taj Mahal ?",
        "optionOne":   "23",
        "optionTwo":   "22",
        "optionThree": "24",
        "optionFour":  "29",
        "rightAnswer": "optionTwo",
        "audiencePoll":"12, 65, 15, 18, 0",
        "amount":      "80,000",
        "information": "With construction beginning around 1632 and finishing in 1653, the Taj Mahal took an estimated 22 years to build."
    },
    {
        "question":    "Which Planet Is Known To Have The Largest Number Of Moons ?",
        "optionOne":   "Venus",
        "optionTwo":   "Mars",
        "optionThree": "Jupiter",
        "optionFour":  "Saturn",
        "rightAnswer": "optionFour",
        "audiencePoll":"8, 5, 25, 62, 0",
        "amount":      "1,60,000",
        "information": "Saturn has overtaken Jupiter. A team discovered a haul of 20 new moons orbiting the ringed planet, bringing its total to 82; Jupiter, by contrast, has 79 natural satellites."
    },
    {
        "question":    "What Is The Full Version Of ISRO ?",
        "optionOne":   "Indian Space Research Organisation",
        "optionTwo":   "Indian Space Reform Organisation",
        "optionThree": "Indian Sub Reformative Organisation",
        "optionFour":  "International Space Research Organisation",
        "rightAnswer": "optionOne",
        "audiencePoll":"78, 12, 5, 5, 0",
        "amount":      "3,20,000",
        "information": "Indian Space Research Organisation, formed in 1969, superseded the erstwhile INCOSPAR (Indian National Committee for Space Research)."
    },
    {
        "question":    "Which Language Is Spoken Popularly In Brazil ?",
        "optionOne":   "Brazilian",
        "optionTwo":   "Portuguese",
        "optionThree": "Danish",
        "optionFour":  "French",
        "rightAnswer": "optionTwo",
        "audiencePoll":"8, 42, 15, 15, 20",
        "amount":      "6,40,000",
        "information": "Brazil accounts for a large portion of both South America’s geography and Portuguese is the official and national language of Brazil."
    },
    {
        "question":    "Which country is known as the largest producer of gold ?",
        "optionOne":   "China",
        "optionTwo":   "Brazil",
        "optionThree": "South Africa",
        "optionFour":  "India",
        "rightAnswer": "optionOne",
        "audiencePoll":"80, 8, 8, 2, 2",
        "amount":      "12,50,000",
        "information": "China is the largest producer of gold in the world and is accounted for around 12 per cent of total global production."
    },
    {
        "question":    "Which is the smallest continent in the world ?",
        "optionOne":   "Asia",
        "optionTwo":   "Australia",
        "optionThree": "Antarctica",
        "optionFour":  "Europe",
        "rightAnswer": "optionTwo",
        "audiencePoll":"2, 88, 6, 1, 3",
        "amount":      "25 Lakh",
        "information": "There are seven continents in the world and Asia is the largest, and according to land-mass, Australia is the smallest at almost a fifth of the size of Asia."
    },
    {
        "question":    "Which is the largest ocean in the world ?",
        "optionOne":   "Atlantic Ocean",
        "optionTwo":   "Indian Ocean",
        "optionThree": "Pacific Ocean",
        "optionFour":  "Arctic Ocean",
        "rightAnswer": "optionThree",
        "audiencePoll":"12, 5, 78, 5, 0",
        "amount":      "50 Lakh",
        "information": "Also the deepest of the world ocean basins, Pacific Ocean covers approx.63 million square miles and containing more than half of the free water on Earth. All the continents could fit into it."
    },
    {
        "question":    "What is called as the World’s Tallest Grass ?",
        "optionOne":   "Wild Grass",
        "optionTwo":   "Bamboo",
        "optionThree": "Lawn Grass",
        "optionFour":  "Silver Grass",
        "rightAnswer": "optionTwo",
        "audiencePoll":"12, 15, 58, 15, 0",
        "amount":      "1 Crore",
        "information": "The Dragon bamboo also known as Giant Bamboo is the tallest known Grass in the world. In Favorable Condition, it can grow maximum up to 40-45 m height- average height 20-25 m."
    },
    {
        "question":    "Who was the man of the match in Cricket World Cup Final of 1983 ?",
        "optionOne":   "Sunil Gavaskar",
        "optionTwo":   "Mohinder Amarnath",
        "optionThree": "Kapil Dev",
        "optionFour":  "Sandeep Patil",
        "rightAnswer": "optionTwo",
        "audiencePoll":"5, 60, 18, 15, 5",
        "amount":      "3 Crore",
        "information": "Mohinder Amarnath was the Man of the Match in the semifinal against England and in the final against the West Indies."
    },
    {
        "question":    "Which Country Will Be Hosting The Olympics In The Year 2020 ?",
        "optionOne":   "Japan",
        "optionTwo":   "South Korea",
        "optionThree": "South Africa",
        "optionFour":  "USA",
        "rightAnswer": "optionOne",
        "audiencePoll":"50, 15, 10, 15, 10",
        "amount":      "5 Crore",
        "information": "Olympics in 2020 has been awarded to Tokyo, which was chosen over fellow Candidate Cities Istanbul and Madrid after two rounds of voting."
    },
    {
        "question":    "Who Is Known As The Founder Of The Social Networking Site, Facebook apart from Mark Zuckerberg ?",
        "optionOne":   "Andrew McCollum",
        "optionTwo":   "Chris Hughes",
        "optionThree": "Eduardo Saverin",
        "optionFour":  "Dustin Moskovitz",
        "rightAnswer": "optionThree",
        "audiencePoll":"10, 15, 50, 15, 10",
        "amount":      "7 Crore",
        "information": "Eduardo Luiz Saverin is a Brazilian entrepreneur. Saverin is one of the co-founders of Facebook. In 2012, he owned 53 million Facebook shares, valued at approximately $2 billion at the time."
    }
  ]
}